<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>Admin</author>
  <title>Taking the next step</title>
  <description>Over the years I have bogged in various locations but have not been diligent about maintaining them </description>
  <content>&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;Over the years I have bogged in various locations but have not been diligent about maintaining them or posting relevant information. &amp;nbsp;That stops today! &amp;nbsp;I want to do more and help others out with what I have learned and what I learn on a daily basis. So what does that mean? For today it means "How do you better yourself using other peoples experiences?"&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Follow leaders in your field. For me I like to follow people like &lt;a href="http://www.hanselman.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Scott Hanselman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://blog.jongallant.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Jon Gallant&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and their blogs. &amp;nbsp;I listen to podcasts from &lt;a href="http://www.techguylabs.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Leo Laporte&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="http://winsupersite.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Paul Thurrott&lt;/a&gt;(but that has ended). &amp;nbsp;I have also been following live streams like&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://live.asp.net/" target="_blank"&gt;live.asp.net&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;over the past year and even using &lt;a href="https://channel9.msdn.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Channel 9&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But these are just some of the&amp;nbsp;various people and media I follow. I love using Twitter to get my daily news feed. I find people that are leaders in my field and see what they do and who they follow and how they relate to me and what I do. &amp;nbsp;If I find what they do and say valuable I continue to follow them, otherwise I stop and maybe I will check back on their site/podcast sometime in the future.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Find someone to mentor you, someone that will push and challenge you. &amp;nbsp;I like to think that if you are comfortable then you are not pushing yourself. &amp;nbsp;You should be constantly pushing yourself, learning, growing, gaining new experiences. &amp;nbsp;I like to use sites like &lt;a href="http://codekata.com/" target="_blank"&gt;CodeKata&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://projecteuler.net/" target="_blank"&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to help sharpen my thinking. Think about things that maybe my job does not require me to think about. &amp;nbsp;Whatever it is, find someone or something to push you to better yourself. &amp;nbsp;This can apply to you and your life in every aspect.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Lastly is, just take time to think. &amp;nbsp;I do some of my best thinking when I step away, when I am able to clear my head, take a moment to myself and focus my energy. Don't be afraid to get up and walk around and think. &amp;nbsp;You will be amazed at what this can do for you if you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; With all that said I am planning out what my next posts will be for the next few months and look forward to putting down in this blog some helpful information for those that come and read it.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2016-02-08 18:21:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2016-03-28 17:25:29</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>taking-the-next-step</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>